# Christopher Cunningham

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER



chrscnnnghm.com



(+34) 643 849 074



christopherpaulcunningham@gmail.com

# **PROFILE**

I'm a front-end developer with a BSc honours degree in Computing Science hoping to rejoin the industry after an extended career break.

With more than two years of industry experience in an ASP .Net development role, I decided to take a break to work with an international NGO in the Philippines and travel. I now live in Valencia, where I am very happy to call home, and feel like it's the perfect time to resume my career.

I consider myself a self-motivated, hardworking person who enjoys learning and is able to get up to speed with new technologies quickly. With proven success in both an individual and team setting, I'm confident I can be an asset to any development team.

I'm currently available for work in Valencia or in a remote capacity, and would also consider relocating for the right opportunity.

Please see my portfolio website above for sample projects.

### **SKILLS**

#### Languages:

JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS (SASS), C#, Java

#### **Libraries & Frameworks:**

React, Node.js, Express, jQuery

#### Others:

MongoDB, SQL Server, Git, Heroku, **Netlify** 

# **EDUCATION**

# **BSc (Hons) Computing Science**

Ulster University | 2010-2014

Graduating with a 1st Class Honours degree classification, I gained experience in a wide range of computing disciplines including software engineering, web development and network technologies.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Front-end Developer

Valencia, Spain | January 2021 - Present

- · As a freelance developer, over the last few months I've produced tailor-made solutions for a number of clients.
- Projects include static landing pages for local businesses, refactoring existing codebases, and work on an e-commerce web application.

## **Expansion Executive @ Jeff**

Valencia, Spain | October 2019 - October 2020

· Responsible for selling Jeff's franchises in Kenya and South Africa as part of their expansion team.

Note: During the gap between these roles I lived in Australia on a working holiday visa and travelled extensively in Asia before returning to Europe.

#### Team Leader @ All Hands Volunteers

Tacloban, Philippines | June 2015 - April 2016

- In the aftermath of Typhoon Yolanda, I joined Project Leyte, a disaster response and recovery project in the Philippines.
- · Although I initially joined as a volunteer, as a testament to my work ethic and ability I was later selected for the position of team leader.
- Working alongside local workers and international volunteers, I was involved in the construction of permanent housing, an elementary school classroom, a multi-purpose community evacuation centre, and a dormitory for orphans.
- · As team leader I was responsible for managing and overseeing the volunteers on the work site, as well as progress of the site and site safety.
- In addition to onsite work, I also attended meetings with local beneficiaries and project management, both locally and in the US, and ensured that the work on my site was progressing as scheduled.

### Associate Software Engineer @ Liberty IT

Belfast, Northern Ireland May 2012 - October 2013 & June 2014 - June 2015

- · Worked as a member of an agile software development team, creating ASP .Net web application solutions for Liberty Insurance.
- As an associate software engineer it was my duty to be involved in the entire software development life cycle, from design and construction to testing, and work to ensure that projects were delivered on time and to specification.
- Responsible for building collaborative relationships with customers and stakeholders, thereby helping to ensure that all products were delivered as needed.
- · Encouraged to get involved in organisational growth and improvement, I was involved in a number of innovations and even proposed one which was later approved and implemented.
- Due to my work ethic and ability in the role, I was not only asked to extend my placement experience by two months, but was also offered a position after graduating, where I worked for a year before leaving to travel.